youth1.com 2019-04-13

# Privacy Statement | Youth1

##### DATE OF LAST REVISION: APRIL 17TH, 2014

Information Collection and Use

Youth1 LLC is the sole owner of the information collected on Youth1. Youth1 LLC collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our website.

IP Addresses  
Youth1 logs IP addresses, in other words, the location of your computer on the Internet, for system administration, troubleshooting, and to examine overall traffic trends. IP addresses are not linked to any personal information. This information, in aggregate form, is recorded for administrative purposes only but may be used, when necessary, to enforce our terms of service or protect our site, network, advertisers or users.

Cookies  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. Login information is stored in a session ID cookie for branding administration, moderators, and the account management system as well as the administration area for the site owner. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. When enabled on our site, votes and ratings are stored in persistent cookies that typically have a life of 30 days. This is the mechanism that tries to stop users from voting or rating the same site multiple times. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file.

Financial Information  
If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information, such as name, address, email and financial information, such as credit card number and expiration date.

Personal Identifying Information  
We collect contact information, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, URL, website title, description and keywords through various registration forms, affiliate and advertising programs, surveys and sweepstakes entry forms. Certain services, such as our community, affiliate and advertising programs, link exchanges and forums require users to enter a unique username and password.

Tell-A-Friend  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name, email address or telephone number. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site or call them if they do not have an email address. Youth1 LLC stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email or call and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [info@youth1.com](mailto:info@youth1.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our web site. These companies may use aggregated infromation (not including your name, address, emal address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

Accessing, Changing, and Sharing Your Personal Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you can access and update your personal information at any time directly using the appropriate control panel on our website or contact Youth1 Support Services by emailing [info@youth1.com](mailto:info@youth1.com). To protect your privacy and security, we will take precautions to verify your identity before granting access or updating your personal information. We respect your right to privacy. We will not rent or sell your personal information or email address to third party outside of Youth1 Media without your consent.

Choice/Opt-Out Of Promotional and Marketing Communications

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preferences on our order form. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [info@youth1.com](mailto:info@youth1.com) and writing "Opt-Out" in the subject line. Some of our services, such as our community, forums and directory services, require registered participants to receive system announcements, invoices or other official communications from Youth1. Users of these services must receive these important notifications as a condition of service.

Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. Whenever we need to collect sensitive personal information such as credit card information on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). While on a secure page information that you provide, such as your name or credit card number, is encrypted so that it can not be read by other people. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about the security on our web site, please email [info@youth1.com](mailto:info@youth1.com).

Forums, Community and Groups

If you use a community or forum on this site you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other community and forum users, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit. Youth1 LLC reserves the right to terminate the accounts of users who use these services in a manner inconsistent with our Terms of Service. Please review the Terms of Service during registration.

Business Transitions

In the event Youth1 LLC goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and a notice will be placed on our home page for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

Other Site Links and Co-Branded Sites

This website contains links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by Youth1 LLC. We cannot be responsible for their content or for private information that you may choose to share with them. Please be aware that we, Youth1 LLC, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Information you release directly to parties who provide services to Youth1 LLC, such as any vendors or other sites you encounter on the Internet may be subject to different rules of use or disclosure. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website.

Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our website.

Changes In This Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here or by means of a notice on our home page.
